Kevin Luke Martin

58 George Street Portsmouth PO15QY

kevin@lukemind.com - 07955482627

Website: https://www.professorperson.app
Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kmartin729

PERSONAL PROFILE

A junior software developer with 2 years commercial experience. I have experience working in an agile environment and have contributed suggestions on renovating their old system, while meeting deadlines adding time slot data in a new page for their new system. I am constantly learning by maintaining and debugging my websites, and LinkedIn courses to learn frameworks including Spring boot and AngularJS. I am always motivated to contribute to the success of the companies I work with as well as their customer's satisfaction.

SKILL SET

- Full stack Java EE XML MYSQL JavaScript
- Networking REST WebSockets Postman
- Android Activities, Layouts, List views, Stomp Client

WORK EXPERIENCE

<u>Level Entry Developer – Open Gi – 2022 to Present</u>

Open Gi provides web services for brokers allowing larger access to products and policies, providing the best quote for the customer. I am working with the ecommerce team, working with a mapper their system OpenQuote uses to translate soap risk so the system can communicate with our partnered company, Mobius. Roles include developing solutions to extend the mapper for Bike Risk, and extend to trucks etc. unit testing, and scalability testing.

Junior Developer - Transalis - 2019 to 2020

Transalis connects suppliers with their customers via EDI (Electronic data interchange) software to allow fast and easy transference of transaction files between suppliers (our clients) and trading partners, such as John Lewis, Tesco, Asda etc. My roles involved accessing Transalis's server via remote desktop, running a batch script to create a new profile for the client and/or configure the routing between the trading partner and our server by altering another batch script. Then email the trading partner asking to send a test order via AS2.

<u>Java Developer – Stannah – 2017 to 2018</u>

This was a placement during my undergraduate course. Worked in an agile environment, with daily standup meetings with a team. My role was to develop a screen for stairlift engineers to log their jobs and time slots and check with masternaut's REST API, as well as tasks and bugs on the HR and sales screen to sum and display order costs. While developing business logic I would perform the calculations to verify the code. Learned freemarker template (FTL), groovy, and MVC pattern, groovy business logic, model data, entityQuery apache Ofbiz.

Achievements

 Designed a database schema combining fields from different tables, reducing complexity and time searching tables for data.

INTERESTS

- Neural networks and computer vision Interested in machine learning methods that allow
 computers to learn human inputs, such as sounds and images. I have developed a neural
 network which can learn from supervised data, and currently developing a convolutional
 neural network which uses that neural network to detect pixel patterns.
- Yachting Enjoys fishing and sailing, learning about electronics on my Dad's boat, who
 shows me how to wire up components to the busbar and charging systems including solar
 panels and a wind turbine. Completed Royal yachting association (RYA)'s Day skipper course
 and Meco training's Boat electronics course.

Education

<u>University of Portsmouth – 2020 to 2021</u>

Postgraduate diploma in Creative Technologies: Pass

Explored my interest in using machine learning in video games, and developed a reinforcement learning agent that reacts to the players actions. Learned how to develop a game loop per frame, render a canvas to a frame with Java's Swing library, multidimensional arrays. The project idea was a q-learning that acknowledges its states or observations of combat actions the player performs, and will learn to defend and attack based on the damage taken during the level.

<u>University of Portsmouth – 2015 to 2019</u>

BSc (Hons) Computing: 2:1

Developed understanding of OOP and the 4 concepts of the paradigm as well as web development, networking protocols, Remote procedure call and database development and management. Utilised this knowledge to develop a dynamic website built with servlets and JSPs that connects to a MYSQL database using Java's database connection library. My final year project was a mobile app allowing users to code on their phones by drawing patterns which are put through a neural network to determine a block of generic code, like a class, method or a statement. This was intended as a faster method to code on a mobile device.

Achievements

• Developed a 2D game in python for a competition and won a wireless keyboard.

Highbury College - 2015

GCSE: Mathematics (A*)

Portsmouth College – 2013 to 2015

A Levels: ICT (B) Applied Science (C)

BTEC: Subsidiary Diploma in Creative Media (Games Development) (Distinction Star)

Highbury College – 2011 to 2013

Pre-16 Vocational Construction Programme in Skills towards Enabling Progression

St Edmunds Catholic School – 2007 to 2013

BTEC: ICT (Distinction), Hospitality (Merit)

GCSE: Additional Science (B) RE (B) English (C) Mathematics (C) Core Science (C) Geography (C)